Guide to the Vice-President for Development and Alumni Affairs, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Vice-president for development and alumni affairs, Yale University, records
1959-1989
RU 537
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
33
(42 boxes)
The records consist of memoranda, correspondence, reports, and financial records documenting the activities and operations of the vice-president for development and alumni affairs. The files of Charles E. Lord, John A. Wilkinson, and Terry Holcombe detail the activities of major administrative figures. Materials related to the Yale Alumni Fund are also included.
Yale University. Office of Development and Alumni Affairs
Dodge, Marshall
Dunham, Lawrence B.
Holcombe, Terry
Lord, Charles E.
Wilkinson, John Arthur, 1938-
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 7-A (YRG 7-A), Records of Yale officers and offices responsible for development policy and administration.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of memoranda, correspondence, reports, and financial records documenting the activities and operations of the vice-president for development and alumni affairs. The files of Charles E. Lord, John A. Wilkinson, and Terry Holcombe detail the activities of major administrative figures. Materials related to the Yale Alumni Fund are also included.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Educational fund raising; Endowments; Fund raising; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Endowments; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Office of Development and Alumni Affairs; Yale University. Yale Alumni Fund
- Marshall J. Dodge report, 1959; Accession 1960-A-001
- Institutional Relations and Alumni Programs reports, 1970-1978; Accession 1979-A-053
- Records of Charles E. Lord, 1972-1979; Accession 1980-A-006
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2054.
  - Yale Alumni Fund (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Yale Alumni Fund, minutes (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Alumni and Friends" A-B (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Alumni and Friends" C-F (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Alumni and Friends" G-H (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Alumni and Friends" I-M (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Alumni and Friends" N-S (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Alumni and Friends" T-Z (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "A Ward to the Y's," Annual reports (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Yale Alumni Publication
    - Yale Alumni Journal (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Yale Alumni Magazine (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Yale Alumni Magazine & Journal, Alumni survey results (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Yale Alumni Publications, minutes, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Yale Alimni Publications, minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Yale Alumni Publications, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Yale University Printing Service, correspondence (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Yale University Printing Service, Financial Statements (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Yale University Printing Service, Annual report to the President and Fellows, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Yale University Printing Service, Report of Greer Allen on the University of Texas at Austin, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Yale Corporation
- Memoranda and chronological files of John A. Wilkinson, 1979-1981; Accession 1981-A-010
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017.
- Records, 1973-1983; Accession 1983-A-015
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019.
- Records of Lawrence B. Dunham as Director of Development and Admissions Policy, 1959-1973; Accession 1984-A-011
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023.
  - "Interviews" - Meetings - "to learn what Yale is all about today", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Yale Club of New York, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Yale Corporation: names and addresses, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Yale School of Medicine--Fischer, James J.--- news release, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Women, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Yale College Daughters and Sons (compared with Harvard College), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 81)
- Chronological files of Terry Holcombe, 1983-1984; Accession 1984-A-012
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2020.
- Chronological files of Terry Holcombe, 1984-1985; Accession 1986-A-099
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021.
- Chronological files of Terry Holcombe, 1985-1986; Accession 1987-A-099
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022.
- Chronological files of Terry Holcombe, 1986-1987; Accession 1988-A-079
- Correspondence, 1987-1988; Accession 1990-A-011
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2024.
- Records of Terry Holcombe, 1978-1989; Accession 1990-A-047
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025.
  - Medical School Campaign, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 31 - 34)